Abhishek Singh

2585 GOUR EKTA MARKT JABALPUR M.P +91 9425795216 Theabhisheksingh@outlook.com https://linkedin.com/in.thesinghabhishek https://theabhisheksingh.github.io

Accomplished professional with 1+ years of facilitating in the IT industry with the experience leading in Agile Project management, Scrum, Client Handling, Requirement Gathering, Design Solutions, wireframing Closely working with Data Science projects Development and operations. Unexcelled record of bringing mission-critical projects in on Schedule and within budget.

Skills

- Project Planning
- Team Management
- Scheduling
- Documentation Development
- Project Control
- Risk Management
- Wireframing
- JIRA
- Office 365
- AWS
- Google Cloud
- Azure

- Prioritization
- Research
- Critical Thinking
- Leadership
- Communication
- Diplomacy
- Demonstration / Coaching
- Deployment
- GIT
- Apache
- NGINX
- Ubuntu

Experience

DEC. 2019-PRESENT

Agile Project Manager/DevOps [Zolute Technology & Consulting Pvt Ltd, Indore]

- Involved in Planning, designing, and analyzing the requirement, Expert in the understanding of any type of complex requirement, Develop Use case study, Deployment.
- Coordinate with clients on daily basis for Standup calls, backlog management, sprint planning, and work on the new bugs the QA team has raised. Involved in providing Impact Analysis.
- Track details in JIRA for the sprint. Discuss the next steps with the Product Owner and prioritize the backlog
- Managing Amazon Web Services (AWS) and Google cloud platform (GCP) infrastructure with automation.
- Design reports which fit to user requirement for operation use.
- Provide technical and functional development of reporting solutions and data analysis.
- Coordinate developer and QC team to ensure product quality
- Develop Use Case Studies of All type of IT Project
- Expert in Deployment, Server/Hosting/Domain Setup & Migration Services
- Design wireframes

MAR 2018-DEC 2019

Project Manager/Business Analyst / [Drafic Venture, Jabalpur]

- Involved in gathering, analyzing, and documenting business requirements, functional requirements, and data specifications for any IT development work.
- Design reports which fit user requirement for operation use
- Expert in Deployment, Server/Hosting/Domain Setup & Migration Services
- Design wireframes
- Technical Writer
- Involved in Project Planning.
- Create Backlogs as per client requirements.

MAR 2015-DEC 2018

Co-Founder/Business Analyst / [Codeyo Development House, Jabalpur]

- Involved in gathering, analyzing, and documenting business requirements, functional requirements, and data specifications for any IT development work.
- Design reports which fit user requirement for operation use
- Expert in Deployment, Server/Hosting/Domain Setup & Migration Services
- Design wireframes
- Technical Writer
- Involved in Project Planning.
- Create Backlogs as per client requirements.

Education

JUN, 2019

[MCA] / [Rajiv Gandhi Proudyogiki Vishwavidyalaya, Bhopal]

Cumulative CGPA: 8.1 / 10

Provided internship to College Students.

Provided free Classes for Basic Programming Concepts / Cloud Concepts.

Created a Project for Thesis work [Cloud Computing - AWS]

Certification

SEP. 2020

[Agile Development Specialization] / [University of Verginia, Coursera]

- Managing an Agile Team
- Agile Software Development
- Continuous Delivery
- Design Thinking
- Manage JIRA
- Sprint Planning

SEP, 2020

[AWS Fundamentals Specialization] / [AWS, Coursera]

- Aws Cloud
- Cloud Computing Security
- Cloud Applications
- EC2, S3, Load Balancer

SEP, 2020

[Git and GitHub] / [Google, Coursera]

- Version Control System
- Revert Changes
- Pull, Push, Commit
- Bitbucket
- Gitlab

SEP, 2020

[Learning NGINX] / [LinkedIn Learning, LinkedIn]

- Configuring a virtual Host
- Securing Sites with NGINX
- Creating SSL Certificates
- Load Balancing
- Reverse proxies